<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction to Plaintext for Research and Writing</title>
    <link>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Introduction to Plaintext for Research and Writing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What? Why? Who? How?</title>
      <link>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>What? Why? Who? How? # What? # Academic writing in general, and scientific and social scientific writing in particular, requires that we use empirical data to mount an argument. There are many conventions that have become sacrosanct that we both need to use and find quite helpful for fulfilling the task of providing convincing data and a tight argument, grounded in a long line of other worthwhile research. Citations, figures, tables, equations, proofs, diagrams and prose are all key to this endeavor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Terminal</title>
      <link>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The Terminal # Switching to a plain text workflow requires that you adjust the way you interact with your computer. Rather than pointing and clicking and navigating through different windows we will be using what is a primitive technology in computing: the Terminal. It was once the case that all interactions with a computer were done with nothing more than a keyboard, not even a mouse. Of course computing has come a long way and most of your interactions with your computer take place with a mouse, touch pad, or touch screen, and it can be intimidating to approach the terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Organization</title>
      <link>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Project Organization # Working with the terminal requires and instructs you about the file structure of your computer, knowledge of which is important for keeping things organized while you do your research and writing. Project organization refers to two separate and sometimes competing tasks: one is organizing the material you need to learn about the world in a way that is conceptually coherent and helpful to you. The second task is organizing actual computer files in such a way that they are accessible to you and to the software you are working with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Installation # In this chapter I will guide you through a tedious and error prone step in the process of adopting plaintext software: installing all the bits and pieces that we are going to be using. When you use something like Word to write, all you need is Word, but the workflow we are going to be using relies upon different pieces of software that all work together. The good thing about this process is that you only have to do it once, and you won&amp;rsquo;t have to fiddle around with it endlessly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document Composition</title>
      <link>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Using LaTeX, Markdown, pandoc # Now that you are familiar with the Terminal and have installed the software we are going to be using you are ready to begin addressing the core competencies of working with plain text software for your research and writing. The essential workflow that we are adopting here is writing in Markdown, a simple markup langauge with a few extra bells and whistles, and then using the pandoc program to convert these into HTML, PDF, ad Word files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Documents</title>
      <link>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic Documents with RMarkdown # If the last chapter was the heart of the PlainText Working Group, this is the capillaries flowing through that heart: making sure that your arguments are rendered beautifully in a document that can readily prove to others that you conscientiously executed good social scientific research. We are going to approach two very exciting topics: the first is creating dynamic documents with RMarkdown. The second is creating beautiful and reproducible figures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version Control</title>
      <link>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Version Control and Collaboration with git and GitHub # A key part of doing research is being able to account for how you got from your data to you findings, and being able to inspect how your project has changed over time is important to that process of accounting. Whatmore, we all want peace of mind as we do our research so that if we make a mistake, we can go back and do it over again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Larger World</title>
      <link>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>A Larger World # There is more to learn about plain text, and this book just gets you started but hopefully it has given you a substantial command over the most important tools for adopting plain text software for your research and writing. It is as good a moment as any to reiterate that plain text isn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone; it presents complications to your work that some find to be excessive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/hidden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://introtoplaintext.com/docs/book/hidden/</guid>
      <description>This page is hidden in menu # Quondam non pater est dignior ille Eurotas # Latent te facies # Lorem markdownum arma ignoscas vocavit quoque ille texit mandata mentis ultimus, frementes, qui in vel. Hippotades Peleus pennas conscia cuiquam Caeneus quas.
Pater demittere evincitque reddunt Maxime adhuc pressit huc Danaas quid freta Soror ego Luctus linguam saxa ultroque prior Tatiumque inquit Saepe liquitur subita superata dederat Anius sudor Cum honorum Latona # O fallor in sustinui iussorum equidem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
